J 740-833-6287 In https://www.linkedin.com/in/viktor-giordano-2357881bb/ https://github.com/vikjg

#### Statement

Young and driven student who is willing to continue learning and become an asset in the workplace. A mathematics education rooted in theory trained me for critical and concise thinking, while multiple experiences in modeling, data analytics, and artificial intelligence have prepared me for a multitude of technological and industrial challenges.

### Technical Skills

**Programming**: Python, C++, MATLAB, SQL, PyTorch, R

Skills: Data Modeling and Analytics, Mathematical and Statistical Reasoning, Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Report Writing, DevOps tools (Git and Docker)

#### Education

# University of Tennessee

Knoxville, TN

Masters of Science in Mathematics

Aug 2022 - May 2024

- Coursework: Numerical Analysis, Partial Differential Equations, Mathematical Biology, Complex and Real Analysis
- Activities: Treasurer of the Association for Women in Mathematics chapter, member of American Mathematical Society, member of UT Cycling Team.

### The Ohio State University

Columbus, OH

Bachelors of Science in Applied Mathematics, Physics with 3.82 GPA

Aug 2020 - May 2022

- Specializations: Topological Data Analysis, Finite Element Method, Optimization and Calculus of Variations
- Activities: Member of Association for Women in Mathematics, Society of Industrial and Applied Mathematics (SIAM), OSU Cycling Club
- Awards: First place award in Ohio State's SIAM contest for a data driven model to determine federal court justice prejudice.

## Ohio State Academy Program

Columbus, OH

Aug 2018 - May 2020

- Program in which high school students attend Ohio State courses as dual-enrollment students.
- Attended Ohio State's main campus full-time in place of my last two years of high school.

### Experience

# University of Tennessee

Knoxville, TN

Graduate Teaching Assistant

Aug 2022 - present

- Supported basic mathematics classes with well-prepared course materials and timely distributions.
- Independently taught multiple sections of Basic Calculus and College Algebra.
- Designed, administered, and graded original lectures, exams, and assignments.

# **Bo Jackson Elite Sports**

Hilliard, OH

Maintenance Technician

Feb 2019 - Jul 2022

- Diagnosed and independently solved different types of mechanical and electrical system problems in an advanced air-supported structure.
- Repaired sports equipment such as pitching machines, safety netting, and turf fields.
- Operated machinery such as boom lifts and skid-loaders.

## Pertinent Projects

- Extreme learning machines that utilize iterative techniques to approximate least squares solution rather than by computing pseudo-inverses, allowing for incredibly fast training times and low computational costs.
- Analyzing pitch-level Statcast data from different baseball games to generate pitching-related visuals and deriving relevant statistics.
- In the works... master's thesis is focused on creating neural network algorithms for imperfect-information zero-sum games such as variations of Hold'em poker. Ideally, these trained networks will be able to approximate known optimal strategies (Nash equilibria).